[MUSIC]
[음악]
In this module, we talked about how to do regression part.
이 모듈에서 회귀에 대해 알아봤습니다
We talked about how to use it to predict house prices.
회귀를 통해 주택 가격을 예측하는 법을 살펴보았습니다
Now, we're going to build together and pricing notebook using Python to predict
IPython 노트북을 이용해
house prices for a real dataset, based on what's called King County data.
킹 카운티의 실제 데이터를 기반으로 주택 가격 예측을 해보겠습니다
King County is the county or the region where the city of Seattle, where Emmy and
킹 카운티는 시애틀 시의 지역이며 에밀리와 제가
I live, is located.
살고 있는 곳이기도 합니다
So, we're going to take some of the data, it's public record data, and
이 공공 기록 데이터를 가지고
actually build together a regression notebook to predict house prices.
IPython을 만들어서 주택 가격을 예측해 봅시다
So let's get started.
그럼 시작해보겠습니다.
Okay, so here's a blank IPython notebook.
빈 IPython 노트북입니다
And just to start, what I'm going to do is hide the,
우선
first let's change the title, so we're going to
제목을
change the title to predicting house prices.
주택 가격 예측으로 바꿉니다
So we just renamed it, and I like to the view menu and hide the header,
이름은 바꿨고 이제 보기 메뉴의 헤더와 툴바를 숨김 처리 해서
and the toolbar, this part on the bottom, so we have more space on the slide.
공간을 확보하죠
So we done the hiding.
다 됐죠
And the first thing we're going to do is fire up Graph Lab Create,
우선 파이썬 알고리즘을 돌릴 GraphLab Create를
the tool that we're going to use to run some algorithms in Python.
띄울 겁니다
So I'm going to type ask M, and
Esc+m 누르고
I'm going to say fire up graphlab create.
GraphLab Create 띄우기라고 씁니다
So we do that by typing import graphlab.
import graphlab 입력하면
And that just starts up graphlab create.
띄워지죠
Now our task today is to predict house prices.
오늘 할 작업은 주택 가격 예측입니다
So the first thing that we are going to do is to load some
이제 주택 판매 데이터를
house sales data.
읽어들이겠습니다
So this is public data, public record, of house that got sold in the Seattle region.
시애틀 지역에서 팔린 주택들의 공공 데이터, 공공 기록입니다
So, I'm going to call this table data sales,
이 표 데이터에 판매라는 이름을 붙이고
and I'm going to say graphlab .SFrame.
graphlab.SFrame이라고 써줍니다
Remember we talked about SFrame as the data structure for
전 시간에 SFrame이 GraphLab Create에서
representing tabular data in graphlab create?
표 형태 데이터를 담는 자료구조라고 알려드렸지요?
So it's a really fast hour of core data structure, and
빠른 out-of-core 자료구조인데
we're going to load up some house things in there.
주택 정보를 읽어올 겁니다
So this is going to be called home underscore data,
home_data라고 하고
and notice that data is now complete for you, so that just happened then.
방금 IPython 노트북이 자동완성 해줬죠
So if I just type while this is loading up and it's firing up GraphLab Create,
지금 읽고 GraphLab Create을 띄우는데
if I just type sales here, you'll see what that data looks like.
판매라고 입력하면 데이터 형식을 볼 수 있습니다
So I'm going to scroll up a little bit to the top, I just type sales and says,
위로 조금 스크롤업해서 판매라고 입력하면
there was an ID for a date with the sale, the price, number of bedrooms,
ID, 날짜, 가격, 침실 개수,
number of bathrooms, square feet, which is kind of like that American version of
화장실 개수, 평수,
square meters if you're living in other countries, for the house, feet for
대지면적, 층수
the lot of land, number of floors, in a bunch of the categories.
등등이 여러 카테고리로 나옵니다
Whether the house has a view or not, whether it sits on a grade,
시야가 있는지, 경사가 있는지
which means it's on a hill, and a bunch of other measurements.
등등의 측량 수치가 있습니다
We've loaded this house data and it looks pretty cool.
이런 주택 데이터를 읽어들여봤는데 괜찮아 보입니다
The first thing that we're going to do is use graph lab canvas and
이제 GraphLab Canvas를 써서
do a little bit of visualization.
시각화를 해보지요
So what I'm going to do is again, create the cell.
칸을 하나 생성합니다
And this says exploring the data for housing.
주택 데이터 탐색하기라고 씁니다
So housing sales.
주택 판매죠
So we're going to do some data exploration.
데이터 탐색을 할 겁니다
So we're going to take the sales data and I'm going to show, so
판매 데이터를 보여주고
when I type .show, it's going to show some visualization of that data,
.show를 입력하면 데이터를 시각화해서 보여줍니다
and in particular, what I'm going to do is view,
이제 볼텐데 GraphLab이 모든 걸
just rather than letting graphlab do this view, we're going
처리하게 놔두기보다는
to just do a scatter plot, so we'll see what a scatter plot is in a second.
산점도를 그려볼텐데 산점도가 뭔지는 곧 알게 됩니다
We'll just type new scatter plot that relates two variables.
두 변수의 관계를 나타내는 산점도를 그립니다
On the X axis, we're going to have the square feet of living space.
x축은 전용면적을 나타냅니다
And in the y axis, we're going to put the price.
y축은 가격을 나타냅니다
So, what that should show us,
이 그래프는
is the relationship to where square feet of living space and price.
전용면적과 가격의 관계를 보여줍니다
Now, one little trick that I like to do when I create notebooks
약간의 요령이 있는데 노트북을 생성할 때
is that sometimes you push out graph lab canvas in a new tub, but
GraphLab Canvas를 새로운 탭에서 보통 생성하게 되는데
also it's kind of fun to just plot those scatter plots and simple plots
그러지 말고 산점도나 간단한 그래프는
inside the notebook itself, so it can print it off and hand it off to somebody.
노트북 안에서 생성하는 게 프린트 뽑기에 좋습니다
So the way to do that is I can just tell graph lab canvas to set its target,
그러기 위해 GraphLab Canvas 대상을
not to be the browser which is the default target,
기본 대상인 브라우저가 아닌
but to be the ipython notebook.
IPython 노트북으로 설정합니다
I just type canvas.set_target('ipynb'), ipython notebook, and
canvas.set_target('ipynb')라고 입력하면
it's going to plot this scatter plot on the notebook itself.
산점도가 노트북에 그려지게 됩니다
So if I hit enter here, what's going to do is take
엔터를 누르면 두 축을
those two axes and just plot them together.
그래프로 그리게 됩니다
So here we go.
자 이제
On the X axis is the square feet of the house, and the Y axis is the price.
x축은 주택 평수고 y축은 가격입니다
So let's kind of browse this a little bit.
이걸 좀 살펴보죠
So for example, the more square feet they're big houses, so
평수가 클수록 큰 집이니
if I mouse over here you'll see that this big house had 5,990 square feet,
여기 마우스를 갖다대면 이 큰 집은 5990 평방피트임을 확인할 수 있죠
which is pretty big, that's like 600 square meters,
꽤 큰 집인데 아마 600 평방미터는 될 겁니다
and it was sold for $2.2 million, which is quite a lot of money.
220만 달러에 팔렸는데 상당한 금액이죠
Now, you also notice there's a nice relationship,
여기 보시면 적당한 관계가 형성되어 있는데
that the bigger houses tend to cost more.
큰 집이 더 비싸다는 것입니다
There's a big blob of houses here, so
여기 큰 덩어리가 1000에서
most houses are between 1,000 and 3,000 square feet.
3000 평방피트의 주택입니다
And even at this level, see this house over here, it's an outlier.
여기서도 이 집은 이상점이죠
So even though it's only 1,910 square feet, it was sold for $1.5 million.
겨우 1910 평방피트인데도 150만에 팔렸습니다
Well, down here there's a house that is similar 1,700 square feet,
비슷한 크기의 1700 평방피트의 집은
that sold for just $149,000.
14.9만에 팔렸는데 말이죠
This is a big discrepancy.
큰 괴리가 있습니다
And here's the biggest outlier of the dataset.
여기 데이터 세트에서 가장 튄 이상점이 있습니다
This house has 3,730 square feet and got sold for $2.5 million.
3730 평방피드인데 250만에 팔렸죠
[MUSIC]
[음악]